# Bhavani Ramaswamy - STRUCTURAL ENGINEER

Mobile No: +91 9512038083

Email Id: 1905bhavani@gmail.com

**Profile** 

12 years of experience as Structural Engineer Includes 6 Years of it is in Underground Metro Rail projects and Design of Educational Institutions, Private residential developments, Large scale commercial buildings, Public sector Buildings, university and other developments using International and Indian codes, BS, ACI, Euro code, UBC, IBC and Saudi Arabian CODES

Areas covered are Analysis, Design and documentation of RCC and steel structures with wind and seismic loads, Design verification, Shop drawing review. Design Document review, preparing response for FCR, RFI, Co-ordinating with MEP. 15 years of experience in structural drafting includes experience in BIM using REVIT Structures. Conversant with computer Design software's such as STAAD Pro, ETABS, TEDDS, RAM Concept, Revit structures, and AutoCAD

## **Educational and Professional Status**

# Charted Member of the Institution of Engineers, INDIA

M.Tech. Structural Engineering SRM University, Kattankulathur, Chennai – May-2012

CGPA: 8.7 (First class with Distinction)

B.E. Civil Engineering – College of Engineering Guindy Anna University June -2009

Diploma in Civil Engineering - Govt Polytechnic - First Class

## Software Skills

STAAD Pro - V8i

STAAD Foundation 5.1

**TEDDS** 

AutoCAD

#### **Revit-structures**

MS office

**Professional Experience** 

## **ORIENTAL CONSULTANTS INDIA PVT LTD**

**Design Engineer** –UG and Tunnels for Gujarat Metro Rail - May 2018 to till date

Ahmedabad Metro Phase 1 Consist of 6.825km under ground includes 4 Underground stations, Cut and cover ramp, Twin Bored tunnel, launching shaft, NATM (191m), Box pushing (99m). As a GEC Design Engineer-Structures I am responsible for the Design review of 2 Underground Stations of UG1, Cut and cover ramp for UG1 and UG2, All cross passages and NATM.

### MOTT MACDONALD - DOHA, QATAR for Doha Metro

(**Deputation**) - 2015 - 2018

#### PROJECTS HANDLED:

# Doha Metro: (Major station site office )

This project comprises two most Emblematic and stations, Msheireb and Education City Stations. Msheireb station is one of the world's biggest underground station.

Responsibilities include Design document review, Shop Drawing review, Assisting Senior

Engineer in Design submissions, Preparation of responses to FCR, RFI, coordination with MEP, In-charge of Shop drawing team (6-7 people reviewing 150 -200 drawings per week) during team lead's absence.

**Gold Line - Underground** Al Waab, Al-Sudan, Joann, Qatar National Museum Stations, Leading the team of Design Verification. **(DVE)** 

# > OCEC Car park, OMEN

Review the PT slab system for OCEC car park- CP4 & CP-5, based on available Architectural Information, RAM Concept models & drawings received from Contractor.

## > HALLIBURTON QATAR CONSOLIDATION PROJECT, QATAR

Analysis and Design with seismic loads, Modelling in STAAD , Design, Documentation , and Checking the drawings

- Substation
- Fire water tank

## > ENDURANCE COMMUNITY VILLAGE QATAR

Analysis and Design with wind and seismic loads, Documentation, and checking the drawings

- Competition stables (concrete)
- Diagrid roof (Steel)
- Farrier workshop (Steel)
- Indoor pool (steel)

# > ALTURKI BEACH ESTATE, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia

Analysis with wind loads, Design, Documentation, and checking the drawings Code used: Saudi Arabian Building Codes, ACI Code Villa 1, 2, and Retaining wall

## > MALL OF EMIRATES Expansion

Analysis, Design and Document

Supporting structure for LV Cables

- Substation 15 and 16
- East car park External Ramp
- Cross Mall walk
- Maintenance platform 1 & 2

# GEMS American Middle and High school (Preliminary Design)

- Partition wall load calculation
- Loading diagrams
- Column Rundown

## > DILMUNIA Health Island.

- Petrol Interceptor
- > St Kitts Park Hyatt.

Concept design sketches for Structural drawings

- Guest room
- Great house
- Maids room
- Presidential villa
- Back of house
- Camp hyatt
- Fisherman village
- Spa

## > ARAB CENTRE

Column Rundown, Foundation and column design

- Faculty Residences
- Student Residences
- Guest House

## > HYDRABAD METRO

STAAD Model, Detailed Design and Document

• Ameer pet station Steel roof structure on Lower and upper platform

# > SHELL Technology Centre at Bengaluru

- Gate complex- 1, 2 3 and 5
- Car park (Scheme design options )
- Amenity Building (steel)
- Entrance Structures (steel)

## Responsibilities

- Interacting with Lead Engineer and collected the basic information pertaining to the project.
- Analyzing and Designing of frames using STAAD and Designing the elements like footings columns, Beams and slabs using spread sheets in Excel.

- Giving inputs to drafting and checking the drawings
- Preparation of document for submission.

### > ABERDEEN POOL

 Structural Design and Documentation of swimming pool Diving pool and Plant room.

# Responsibilities

- Interacting with Lead Engineer and collected the basic information pertaining to the project.
- Analyzing and Designing of frames using STAAD and Designing the elements like footings columns and slabs in TEDDS.
- Giving inputs to drafting and checking the drawings

### > DLF INFOCITY

Finite element modeling for Raft & Flat slab using STAAD Analysis in STAAD Design in spread sheets in EXCEL

# > JUBAIL UNIVERSITY - (Based on ACI Code)

Structural Design and Documentation of Sub structure and Super structure for

- Male Main Engineering Building
- Female Architecture Buildings
- Male General Studies Building
- using STAAD Pro and STAAD Foundation
- Preparing Structural Bill of Quantities for all 17
- Buildings in JUBAIL University

## Responsibilities

- Interacted with Lead Engineer and collected the basic information pertaining to the project.
- Analyzing and Designing of frames using STAAD and STAAD Foundation Scripting design documentation and estimation using MS Tools and posting them on the Document Manager.
- Preparing Structural BOQ using EXCEL

# > QUATAR PETROLEUM

- Preparing Bill of quantities for all underground structures like
- Fire Valve Chambers
- Sewage Man Holes.
- End user valves
- Civil Consolidated BOQ for the above

# Heathrow T2B

• Correcting the existing FASTRACK Model according to revised Architectural drawing

### > TAREEQ AL MATAR SWTP

- Drainage pumping station Tank
- Preparing Spread sheet in Excel for the Drainage Pumping station Tank 1 and 2

#### Jun 2006 - March 2009

### MOTT MACDONALD

## CAD LEAD - Structural, Chennai, India

Involved in guiding checking and co- coordinating

- Heathrow-T2B
- Justice mill lane R.C. Detailing with BBS
- Birmingham Magistrate court Stag D (Scheme design) an Stag -E (Detailing)
- Ashton Bypass retaining wall R.C. Detailing with BBS
- Avon mouth bridge Standardizing th existing drawing
- Kings Langley car park Layout design
- Karachi enclave Multi storey building
- One Hyde park PT Slab with BBS
- Royal welsh college R C Detailing

# March 2003-May 2006

# ASE DESIGNSOFT PVT LTD

### **Senior Cad Engineer**

### Activities involved:

- Detailing of mobile telecommunication projects for various operators like BASE, ASTRID, MOBISTAR, (in French and Dutch languages)
- Build permit drawings, Preliminary design drawings, Detailed design drawings for Green field and Rooftop sites (Buildings, Church, Water tank etc)
- Equipment drawings & detailing of mechanical fixtures for antenna and equipments.
- Detailed fixation of wall mounted antennas.
- Detailed drawing of profile to profile fixation
- Preparation of foundation details of towers
- Bill of quantities

## June 1992 - March 2003

## SANGAMESWARAN ENGG.CONSULTANTS

## **NATURE OF WORK**

Preparation of detailed structural drawings

### **PROJECTS HANDLED**

- Proposed Cab panel press shop at Hosur for Ashok Leyland Ltd
- Disa Foundry, VIP Guest House at Sholinghur for Brakes India Ltd

- Proposed Fruit & Vegetable Auction Market, Processing Plant, Cold Storage for
- Mother Dairy, Bangalore Fruit & Vegetables Ltd
- Residential Apartments at various Place

Sep- 1988 - May 1999

## M/S PITHVADIAN & PARTNERS

### **NATURE OF WORK**

Preparation of detailed structural drawings

## **PROJECTS HANDLED**

- Annamalai University
- St. Mary's Cathedral at VARANASI
- Rani Meyyammai kalyanamandapam 1 & 2

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Father's Name : R.S. RAMASWAMY

Mothers Name : R. ANANADHAVALLI

Sex : Female
Marital Status : Single

Languages known : Tamil, English, Hindi

Passport No : L7624983

Permanent Address : 1/1282. MGR 2<sup>nd</sup> Street

**Gandhi Nagar, REDHILLS** 

CHENNAI - 600 052.

Current Address G501.Shyam sukan Residency

Bhaijipura Gandhinagar Gujarat-382421

Current CTC 24.84 Lakhs per Annum Expected CTC 29.8 Lakhs per Annum

I hereby declare that all the information furnished herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Ahmedabad, India

Date: 21.01.2022

R. BHAVANI